Matthew Angel

Front End Engineer

23matthewangel@gmail.com

3057739645

Key Biscayne, United States

Passionate Front End Developer focused on enhancing applications and websites using HTML, CSS Javascript and React. Adept in collaborating with Designers and other Developers to execute the user interfaces for client facing pages. Experienced in small and enterprise level environments.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

Gap Inc

08/2022 - 02/2023 Remote

Technologies used: VS Code, React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Jenkins

Achievements/Tasks

- Created and oversaw design requests from team members.
- Oversaw website development for https://www.gap.co.jp/ (Gap's Japanese website).
- Translated designs into high quality code using HTML CSS Javascript and React.
- Debugged front end code with senior developers do address website issues.
- Participated in an Agile environment that consisted of standups twice a week to go over progress, updates and future projects with team leaders.

Front End Developer eMed Digital Healthcare

08/2021 - 08/2022 Technologies used: VS Code, React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Hubspot

Achievements/Tasks

Collaborated with Designers to turn mockups/wireframes into fully functioning web pages.

- Successfully coded a full website overhaul for emed.com that has over a million visitors a month(new header, footer, overall contents on all web pages.
- Built landing pages for clients using Hubspot modules consisting of HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Cross tested website on multiple devices to ensure accuracy in responsive design.
- Contributed to the ecommerce platform that was built with react as the main technology.
- Used Functional Components to Make UI changes along with modern react hooks.

Miami,Fl

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Redline Media Group

12/2020 - 08/2021 Dania, Fl

Achievements/Tasks

- Code responsive emails using HTML CSS and Javascript.
- Create user interfaces, using front-end languages.
- Develop email marketing campaigns.
- Work closely with creative team to decide on best practices for email designs.

Technologies used: VS Code, Javascript, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Adobe Dreamweaver, Vertical Response

- Manage and organize assets for all email campaigns (300+ monthly).
- Analyze and resolve bugs that arise in coding process.

Front End Developer (Contract Role)

NinjaRMM, LLC

08/2020 - 01/2021
Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Wordpress

Achievements/Tasks

- Maintain and improve company website

- Use a variety of programming languages to create user-friendly web pages
- Work as part of a multidisciplinary team with other professionals; such as, back-end developers and web designers
- Designing and managing the website back-end including database and server integration

EDUCATION

Bachelor of English, Editing, Writing, and Media

Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL

08/2015 - 12/2017

Web Development Bootcamp (400+ Hours)

IronhackMiami

07/2020 - 10/2020

Remote